<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<module name="cts_commands" prompt="CTS> " def_file=".cts">
<!-- 
     Copyright (c) 2017, Massachusetts Institute of Technology All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this
list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this
list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or
other materials provided with the distribution.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS"
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
-->

  <helpall>

    CTS (CAMAC Topological System) Commands.

    CTS is used to configure the CAMAC system and assign logical names
    to CAMAC modules assessible via CAMAC serial highway controllers.

    ADDCRATE      - Add a CAMAC crate controller to configuration.
    AUTOCONFIG    - Map scsi devices to CAMAC physical module addresses.
    ASSIGN        - Assign a logical name to a CAMAC module.
    DEASSIGN      - Deassign a logical name.
    DELCRATE      - Delete a CAMAC crate controller from configuration.
    SET           - Turn CAMAC crates on or off.
    SHOW          - Show logical name definitions.
    SHOW/CRATE    - Show status of CAMAC crate controllers.

  </helpall>

  <verb name="assign">
    <help name="assign">
      Command: ASSIGN
      Purpose: Assign a name to a CAMAC module.
      Format: ASSIGN physical-name logical-name [/COMMENT="comment"]

      Description:

      The ASSIGN command can be used to assign a name to a physical CAMAC module address
      so the module can be referenced using a user friendly name.

      CAMAC module physical names look like: GKA123:N10 where the A is the host scsi adapter,
      1 is the scsi id of the serial crate controller, 23 is the crate number of the crate
      and 10 is the slot number of the CAMAC module in the crate. Host scsi adapters are
      named A,B,C etc... and map to the scsi adapters in the /proc/scsi/scsi.

      Logical-names can be up to 32 characters in length and must consist of alphanumeric
      characters and underscores. Logical name lookup is case insensitive.
      The logical-name must be unique but more than one logical-name
      can be assigned to the same physical-name.

      The /COMMENT qualifier can be used to add some information about the module which
      will be displayed using the SHOW command.

      Example:

      ASSIGN GKA410:N01 MY_CAMAC_MODULE /COMMENT="This is my special module"

    </help>
    <routine name="Assign"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="PHY_NAME" required="True" prompt="Physical name:"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="LOG_NAME" required="True" prompt="Logical name:"/>
    <qualifier name="comment"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="autoconfig">
    <help name="autoconfig">

      Command: AUTOCONFIG
      Purpose: Create a map between the physical module names and the host scsi adapters.
      Format: AUTOCONFIG

      Description:

      The physical names of CAMAC modules begin with GKx where x denotes the scsi adapter
      where the camac serial highway is attached. The AUTOCONFIG command looks up the
      list of scsi adapters in /proc/scsi/scsi and makes a map between A,B,C and the
      scsi host adapaters. Normally the AUTOCONFIG command is done once during system
      startup to refresh this mapping information.
    </help>
    <routine name="Autoconfig"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="deassign">
    <help name="deassign">

      Command: DEASSIGN
      Purpose: Remove a logical name assigment to a CAMAC module.
      Format: DEASSIGN name [/PHYSICAL]

      Description:

      Logical names are assigned to physical address names of CAMAC modules to make it
      easier to reference the CAMAC modules when using the CAMAC I/O library routines
      or utilities. These logical names can be defined using the ASSIGN command. The
      DEASSIGN command is used to remove a logical name when it is no longer being
      used. Without specifying the /PHYSICAL qualifier, the name specified should be
      the logical name you want to remove. If you want to remove all logical names
      to a particular CAMAC module you can use the /PHYSICAL qualifier and then use
      the physical name of the module.

      Examples:

      CTS> DEASSIGN MY_MODULE
      CTS> DEASSIGN/PHYSICAL GKA401:N10
      
    </help>
    <routine name="Deassign"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="MODULE" required="True" prompt="Module:"/>
    <qualifier name="physical"/>
  </verb>

  <!--
  <verb name="reset">
    <routine name="ResetHighway"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="MODULE" required="True" prompt="Highway:"/>
  </verb>
  -->
  
  <verb name="set">
    <help name="SET">

      Command: SET
      Purpose: Set a crate controller online or offline
      Format:  SET wild-card-crate-name (/ON | /OFF) [/QUIET]

      Description:

      The SET command can be used to put CAMAC crate controllers online or
      offline. A CAMAC crate controller must be online before CAMAC I/O can
      take place with any modules in that crate except for the crate controller
      itself. You can use wildcards in the crate controller name.

      Examples:

      CTS> SET GKA102/ON
      CTS> SET */ON/QUIET   ! Turn on all the crates without logging errors.
      
    </help>
    <routine name="SetCrate"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="CRATE" default="*"/>
    <qualifier name="online"/>
    <qualifier name="offline"/>
    <qualifier name="quiet"/>
  </verb>
  
  <verb name="show">
    <help name="SHOW">

      Command: SHOW
      Purpose: List logical name table to CAMAC modules
      Format: SHOW [[wild-card-name] [/PHYSICAL]]

      Description:

      The SHOW command will list the logical name to physical name
      mapping for CAMAC modules. With no name specified it will list all the
      defined CAMAC module logical names. Specifying a name will cause the SHOW
      command to only list those modules matching the name specified. If the
      /PHYSICAL qualifier is present, the wild-card-name will be used to match
      the physical-address names of the modules.

      Examples:

      CTS> SHOW             ! list all the defined CAMAC modules
      ...
      CTS> SHOW GKA4*/PHYS  ! list all the modules whose physical names start with 'GKA4'
      ...
      CTS> SHOW ENG*        ! list all the modules whose logical names start with ENG
          #  Logical Name                     Physical   Comment
      ==== ================================ ========== ========================================679
      135: ENG_B2408                        GKA601:N11                                         &lt;
      136: ENG_DECODER                      GKA601:N9                                          &lt;
      137: ENG_ENCODER                      GKA601:N22                                         &lt;
      138: ENG_IGOR                         GKA601:N1  Engineering IGOR (state)                &lt;
      ==== ================================ ========== ========================================
      
    </help>
    <routine name="ShowModule"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="MODULE" default="*"/>
    <qualifier name="crate" syntax="show_crate"/>
    <qualifier name="highway" syntax="show_highway"/>
    <qualifier name="physical"/>
    <qualifier name="format"/>

  </verb>

  <syntax name="show_crate">
    <help name="SHOW/CRATE">

      Command: SHOW/CRATE
      Purpose: Display the status of CAMAC crate controllers
      Format:  SHOW/CRATE [wild-card-name]

      Description:

      The SHOW/CRATE displays the current status of CAMAC crate controllers.
      The list includes the crate's online status (*==online, x==offline),
      and whether the crate controller supports enhanced I/O commands such
      as FSTOP, FQREP and FQSTOP operations. The LAM and PRV columns on the
      list are no longer supported. If a wild-card-name is provides, only
      the crates which match the name are listed.

      Example:

      CTS> show/crate gka51*
      CRATE   ONL LAM PRV ENH
      =======  === === === ===
      GKA510:   X   .   .   -
      GKA512:   *   .   .   *
      GKA514:   *   .   .   -
      GKA515:   *   .   .   -
      GKA516:   *   .   .   -
      GKA517:   X   .   .   -
      GKA518:   *   .   .   -
      =======  === === === ===
      
    </help>
    <routine name="ShowCrate"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="MODULE" default="*"/>
  </syntax>

  <!--
  <syntax name="show_highway">
    <routine name="ShowModule"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="MODULE" default="*"/>
  </syntax>
-->

  <verb name="addcrate">
    <help name="ADDCRATE">

      Command: ADDCRATE
      Purpose: Add a CAMAC crate to the configuration
      Format:  ADDCRATE crate-name (i.e. GKA410)

      Description:

      The ADDCRATE command is used to add CAMAC crates to the CTS system configuration.
      Once a crate is added then you can set the crate online or offline using the SET
      command as well as add logical name mappings to modules in the crate using the
      ASSIGN command.
      
    </help>
    <routine name="AddCrate"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="PHY_NAME" required="True" prompt="Physical name:"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="delcrate">
    <help name="DELCRATE">

      Command: DELCRATE
      Purpose: Delete a CAMAC crate from the CTS configuration.
      Format:  DELCRATE crate-name

      Description:

      The DELCRATE command is used to remove a CAMAC crate from the CTS configuration.
      The crate-name to delete is specified in the command (i.e. DELCRATE GKA410)
    </help>
    <routine name="DelCrate"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="PHY_NAME" required="True" prompt="Physical name:"/>
  </verb>

</module>
