<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<module name="tcl_commands" prompt="TCL> " def_file=".tcl">
<!-- 
     Copyright (c) 2017, Massachusetts Institute of Technology All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this
list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this
list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or
other materials provided with the distribution.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS"
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
-->

  <helpall>
    TCL (Tree Command Language) commands:

    TCL is used for MDSplus tree examination and manipulation. 
    TCL can be used to examine the tree structure, store data to or get data
    from nodes, examine or change node properties, or clean or compress the
    datafile associated with a tree. These commands are listed
    when you type:

    HELP TREE COMMANDS

    TCL can also be used for dispatching commands or actions to action servers
    or to directly execute actions or methods provided by devices described in
    the tree. For help on dispatching related commands type:

    HELP DISPATCH COMMANDS

    With TCL using edit commands you can create a new tree structure or modify
    an existing one by adding, deleting or renaming nodes and adding tagnames
    to give direct addressing of nodes in the tree. For edit commands type:

    HELP EDIT COMMANDS

    TCL can also issue and wait for MDSplus events. See:

    HELP WFEVENT and HELP SETEVENT
  </helpall>

  <help name="EDIT COMMANDS">
    The following commands are available for editing the structure of an MDSplus tree:

    ADD NODE      - Add a node to an MDSplus tree.
    ADD TAG       - Assign a tagname to a node in the tree.
    DELETE NODE   - Delete a node in an MDSplus tree.
    EDIT          - Open a tree or create a new tree for subsequent editing.
    REMOVE TAG    - Remove a tagname.
    RENAME        - Rename a node in a tree.
    SET READONLY  - Mark tree as readonly. No changes to data or nci permitted.
    SET VERSIONS  - Enable data version support in a tree.
    WRITE         - Write out a modified tree committing edit changes.

    Type HELP command-name for more information on the command or
    HELP TREE COMMANDS or HELP DISPATCH COMMANDS for info on additional
    commands.
  </help>
  <help name="TREE COMMANDS">
    The following commands are available for viewing or manipulating data and
    attributes of nodes in a tree:

    CLEAN          - Clean the datafile of a tree reclaiming unused space.
    CLOSE          - Close one or more trees currently open by this process.
    COMPRESS       - Compress a datafile by compressing data records.
    CREATE PULSE   - Create a new pulse file.
    DECOMPILE      - Decompile the data stored in a node.
    DELETE PULSE   - Delete a pulse file.
    DIRECTORY      - List the nodes in a tree.
    DIRECTORY/TAG  - List the tagnames in a tree.
    PUT            - Store data in a node.
    SET ATTRIBUTE  - Set an extended attribute for a node.
    SET CURRENT    - Set the current shot number fo a tree.
    SET DEFAULT    - Change the current location in a tree.
    SET TREE       - Open an MDSplus tree.
    SET VIEW       - Specify a point in time for examining the tree.
                     This command only applies to trees with versioning enabled.
    SHOW ATTRIBUTE - Show an extended attribute for a node.
    SHOW CURRENT   - Show the current shot for a tree.
    SHOW DATA      - Show the data structure stored in a node.
    SHOW DB        - Show the tree currently opened.
    SHOW DEFAULT   - Show the current location in a tree.
    SHOW VERSIONS  - Show whether or not versioning is enabled in the tree.
    VERIFY         - Verify the tree structure of an MDSplus tree.

    Type HELP command-name for more information on the command or
    HELP EDIT COMMANDS or HELP DISPATCH COMMANDS for info on additional
    commands.
  </help>

  <help name="DISPATCH COMMANDS">
    The following commands are available for dispatching
    or executing actions in an MDSplus tree.

    ABORT SERVER     - Abort the action currently executing in an action server.
    DISPATCH         - Dispatch an action node to an action server.
    DISPATCH/BUILD   - Build a dispatch table in preparation for dispatch action phases.
    DISPATCH/CHECK   - Determine if all essential actions completed successfully.
    DISPATCH/CLOSE   - Tell all action servers used to close all tree.
    DISPATCH/COMMAND - Dispatch a commands to an action server.
    DISPATCH/PHASE   - Dispatch the actions associated with an experiment phase.
    DO               - Execute an action in a tree.
    DO/METHOD        - Execute a method provided by a device in a tree.
    SHOW SERVER      - Show the current status of an action server.
    STOP SERVER      - Stop an action server.
    
    Type HELP command-name for more information on the command or
    HELP EDIT COMMANDS or HELP TREE COMMANDS for info on additional
    commands.
  </help>
  
  <verb name="abort">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="abort_type"/>
  </verb>
  <type name="abort_type">
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="abort_server"/>"
  </type>
  <syntax name="abort_server">
    <routine name="TclDispatch_abort_server"/>
    <help name="ABORT SERVER">
      Command: ABORT SERVER
      Purpose: Abort the action currently being executed by an MDSplus action server.
      Format: ABORT SERVER server-name[,server2[,server3...]]
      Description:
      
      The ABORT SERVER command will abort the action currently being executed in an
      MDSplus action server. Actions are executed in servers when dispatched using
      the DISPATCH command.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="stop_type"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="server_name" prompt="Server" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>
  
  <verb name="add">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="ADD_TYPE"/>
  </verb>
  <type name="ADD_TYPE">
    <keyword name="NODE" syntax="add_node"/>"
    <keyword name="TAG" syntax="add_tag"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="add_node">
    <routine name="TclAddNode"/>
    <help name="ADD NODE">
      Command: ADD NODE
      Purpose: Add a new node to a tree opened for edit.
      Format: ADD NODE node-path [/USAGE=usage]|[/MODEL=device-type]
      Description:

      The ADD NODE command is used to add a new node to an MDSplus tree which has been
      opened using the EDIT command. The node-path parameter specified the name of the
      new node to be added. It can be an absolute node path or a relative node path. If
      the path name includes parent nodes, those parent nodes must already exist or the
      command will fail. Node names must begin with an alphabetic character followed by
      zero or more alphanumeric or underscore characters. The node name must be 12
      characters or less in length.

      The /USAGE qualifier specifies a usage type of the node. This must be one of:
      ACTION, ANY, AXIS, COMPOUND_DATA, DEVICE, DISPATCH, NUMERIC, SIGNAL,
      STRUCTURE, SUBTREE, TEXT or WINDOW. If not specified, a member node (:name) will
      default to usage ANY and a child node (.name) will default to usage STRUCTURE.

      If adding a device (i.e. data acquisition device) use the /MODEL qualifier to
      specify the type of supported device you are adding.

      NOTE: The ADD NODE command can only be used when a tree is opened for edit.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="ADD_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODENAME" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="model" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="usage" defaulted="True" default="ANY"/>
    <!--
	<qualifier name="qualifiers"/>
    -->
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="add_tag">
    <routine name="TclAddTag"/>
    <help name="ADD TAG">
      Command: ADD TAG
      Purpose: Add a tag to a node.
      Format: ADD TAG node-path tagname
      Description:

      The ADD TAG command is used to add a tagname to a node. A tagname is
      kind of a shortcut for referencing a node in the tree. You don't need
      to known the full path location of the node if you reference it by its
      tagname. For example if a node has a tagname of "ip" you could reference
      that node by using \ip or \treename:ip. The tagname has to be unique
      for a given tree. Tagnames can be up to 23 characters in length and must
      consist of an alphabetic character followed by up to 22 alphanumeric or
      underscore characters.

      NOTE: The ADD TAG command can only be used when you have opened the tree
      using the EDIT command.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="ADD_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p3" label="TAGNAME" prompt="Tag" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="clean">
    <routine name="TclCleanDatafile"/>
    <help name="CLEAN">
      Command: CLEAN
      Purpose: Clean unused space in the trees datafile.
      Format: CLEAN treename [/SHOT=shot-number]
      Description:

      As data is written to a tree if the record is greater than 16 bytes
      in length it is appended to the end of the tree's datafile. When the
      data in a node is modified, unless the size of the data is exactly the
      same length as was previously stored, the new data is appended at the
      end of the datafile. The previous data continues to occupy it's original
      space in the datafile and will not be reused. The CLEAN command can be
      used to recover this wasted space. When the command is issued, the
      datafile is recreated by reading in the current data for each node and
      writing it to the new datafile thus discarding the orphaned data in
      the file.

      The CLEAN command is similar to the COMPRESS command except the COMPRESS
      command will also employ data compression on the data records often
      drastically reducing the file size if the nodes were not set to be
      compressed on put.

      Since both the CLEAN and COMPRESS command create new datafiles, it is
      recommended that they only be used when there is unlikely to be any other
      write activity on the tree.

      Note: The shot number may be expressed as a TDI expression. For example,
      CLEAN cmod/shot="CURRENT_SHOT(""CMOD"")-1"
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="FILE" prompt="File" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1" type="number"/>
    <qualifier name="override"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="close">
    <routine name="TclClose"/>
    <help name="CLOSE">
      Command: CLOSE
      Purpose: Close the current tree or all open trees.
      Format: CLOSE [treename [/SHOT=shot-number]]|[/ALL][/CONFIRM]
      Description:

      Using the CLOSE command without any parameters or qualifiers will close the last
      tree opened with either a SET TREE command or an EDIT command. Since TCL will keep
      a stack of previously opened trees you can selectively close a particular tree by
      specifying the treename anr shot number information or to close all the tree, use
      CLOSE/ALL. To determine which trees you currently have open you can use the SHOW DB
      command.

      Note: You must use the WRITE command on a tree opened using the EDIT command if you
      want to save and edits you might have done to that tree before using the CLOSE
      command to close it. If you attempt to close a tree with edit modifications you
      will get an error unless you force the close using the /CONFIRM qualifier. If you
      close and modified tree with the /CONFIRM qualifier the tree will be closed and any
      edit modification will be discarded.

      Note: The shot number may be expressed as a TDI expression. For example,
      CLOSE cmod/shot="CURRENT_SHOT(""CMOD"")-1"
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="FILE"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1" type="number"/>
    <qualifier name="confirm"/>
    <qualifier name="all"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="compress">
    <routine name="TclCompressDatafile"/>
    <help name="COMPRESS">
      Command: COMPRESS
      Purpose: Compress the tree's datafile.
      Format: COMPRESS treename [/SHOT=shot-number]
      Description:

      As data is written to a tree if the record is greater than 16 bytes
      in length it is appended to the end of the tree's datafile. When the
      data in a node is modified, unless the size of the data is exactly the
      same length as was previously stored, the new data is appended at the
      end of the datafile. The previous data continues to occupy it's original
      space in the datafile and will not be reused. The COMPRESS command can be
      used to recover this wasted space. When the command is issued, the
      datafile is recreated by reading in the current data for each node and
      writing it to the new datafile thus discarding the orphaned data in
      the file.

      The COMPRESS command is similar to the CLEAN command except the COMPRESS
      command will also employ data compression on the data records often
      drastically reducing the file size if the nodes were not set to be
      compressed on put.

      Since both the CLEAN and COMPRESS command create new datafiles, it is
      recommended that they only be used when there is unlikely to be any other
      write activity on the tree.

      Note: The shot number may be expressed as a TDI expression. For example,
      COMPRESS cmod/shot="CURRENT_SHOT(""CMOD"")-1"
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="FILE" prompt="File" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1" type="number"/>
    <qualifier name="override"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="create">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="CREATE_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="CREATE_TYPE">
    <keyword name="PULSE" syntax="create_pulse"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="create_pulse">
    <routine name="TclCreatePulse"/>
    <help name="CREATE PULSE">
      Command: CREATE PULSE
      Purpose: Copy the currently open tree (usually the model, shot -1) into a pulse
               file.
      Format: CREATE PULSE shot-number [/INCLUDE=(subtree1,subtree2,...)]
              [/EXCLUDE=(subtree1,subtree2,...)] [/CONDITIONAL] [/NOMAIN]

      Description:

      The CREATE PULSE command will copy the currently opened tree and all it's subtrees
      (unless the optional qualifiers are specified) to pulses with the specified shot
      number.

      The /INCLUDE, /EXCLUDE, /CONDITIONAL and /NOMAIN qualifiers can be used to
      customize which trees will be included in the new pulse files. Specifying the
      /CONDITIONAL qualifier will cause the command to examine the "include in pulse"
      characteristic (set by SET NODE command and view by the DIR/FULL command) of the
      subtree nodes to decide if that subtree should be included. The /INCLUDE and
      /EXCLUDE qualifiers can take a list of node paths to specify which subtree nodes
      to include or exclude. If the /INCLUDE qualifier is specified only the subtrees
      specified will be included. If the /EXCLUDE qualifier is specified, all but the
      subtrees specified will be include. If the /NOMAIN qualifier is included the top
      most tree will not be included in the new pulse files.

      NOTE: The shot number may be specified as a TDI expression such as
      "CURRENT_SHOT(""CMOD"")+1".
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="CREATE_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="shot" prompt="Shot number" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="include" required="True" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="exclude" required="True" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="conditional"/>
    <qualifier name="nomain" nonnegatable="True"/>
    <qualifier name="dispatch"/>
  </syntax>
 
  <verb name="DECOMPILE">
    <routine name="TclDecompile"/>
    <help name="DECOMPILE">
      Command: DECOMPILE
      Purpose: Display the contents of a node in the tree.
      Format: DECOMPILE node-path

      Description:

      The DECOMPILE command will display the contents of a node in the tree. If the data
      converted to a string exceeds approximately 30,000 characters the string representation
      of large arrays will be truncated.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="PATH" required="True"/>
    </verb>
 
  <!--
  <type name="DEFINE_TYPE">
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="define_server"/>"
  </type>
  -->

  <!--
  <verb name="DEFINE">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="WHAT" required="True" type="DEFINE_TYPE"/>
  </verb>


  <syntax name="define_server">
    <routine name="TclCreatePulse_server"/>
    <help name="DEFINE SERVER">
      Command: DEFINE SERVER never implemented for linux/windows
      Purpose: The DEFINE SERVER command specifies an MDSplus server to be responsible
               for creating pulse files for particular tree(s).
      Format: DEFINE SERVER/TREE=(treename1[,treename2...]) server-name

      Description:

      The DEFINE SERVER command specifies actions server which should be used for creating
      MDSplus pulse files for particular trees. The server definitions are used by the
      CREATE PULSE command to distribute the pulse creation to distributed servers. For
      more information on this see HELP CREATE PULSE.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="WHAT" required="True" type="DEFINE_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="tree" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>
  -->
  
  <verb name="delete">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="DELETE_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="DELETE_TYPE">
    <keyword name="NODE" syntax="delete_node"/>"
    <keyword name="PULSE" syntax="delete_pulse"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="delete_node">
    <routine name="TclDeleteNode"/>
    <help name="DELETE NODE">
      Command: DELETE NODE
      Purpose: Delete one or more nodes in a tree opened for edit.
      Format: DELETE NODE node-path[,node-path...] /LOG /CONFIRM /DRYRUN

      Description:

      The DELETE NODE command is used to delete node(s) from an MDSplus tree. The tree
      must be opened for edit using the EDIT command. If you attempt to delete a node
      which has descendants or is part of a device (conglomerate) representation in the
      tree then the deletion of the node will result in multiple nodes being deleted.
      If this is your intention then you must include the /CONFIRM qualifier on the
      command. The /LOG qualifier can be used to display the nodes being deleted.
      The /DRYRUN command can be used to just display the nodes that would be deleted
      without actually deleting any nodes.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="DELETE_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" prompt="Node" label="NODENAME" required="True" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="log"/>
    <qualifier name="confirm"/>
    <qualifier name="DRYRUN"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="delete_pulse">
    <help name="DELETE PULSE">

      Command: DELETE PULSE
      Purpose: Delete an MDSplus pulse file instance of the currently opened tree.
      Format: DELETE PULSE shot-number

      Description:

      The DELETE PULSE command will delete the three files making up an MDSplus tree for
      the specified shot number.
      
      NOTE: If the currently opened tree includes subtrees, those subtrees will be deleted
      for that shot number as well.
      
      For example:
      
        TCL> SET TREE cmod
        TCL> DELETE PULSE 42
      
      This would delete the cmod pulse files for shot number 42 as well as any subtrees of
      the cmod tree with shot number 42.
      
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDeletePulse"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="DELETE_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" prompt="Shot number" label="shot" required="True" type="NUMBER"/>
    <qualifier name="all"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="directory">
    <routine name="TclDirectory"/>
    <help name="DIRECTORY">
      Command: DIRECTORY
      Purpose: List nodes in the tree.
      Format: DIRECTORY [nodepath-wild1[,nodepath-wild2,...]] [/FULL]
                        [/USAGE=(usage1[,usage2,...]) | /USAGE=usage]
      
      Description:

      The DIRECTORY command is used to list one or more nodes in the currently opened tree.
      You can specify one or more node paths which may include wildcard characters. If no
      node paths are specified it defaults to listing the member and child nodes in the current
      location of the tree (See: SET DEFAULT command).

      If the /FULL qualifier is included then detailed information about each node is included.
      Use the /USAGE qualifier if you want to list only nodes of a certain usage. Usage names
      include ACTION, ANY, AXIS, COMPOUND_DATA, DEVICE, DISPATCH, NUMERIC, SIGNAL,
      STRUCTURE, SUBTREE, TEXT or WINDOW.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="NODE" default="*,.*" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="full"/>
    <qualifier name="path"/>
    <qualifier name="usage" list="True" type="USAGE_TYPE"/>
    <qualifier name="tag" syntax="dir_tag_syntax"/>
  </verb>

  <syntax name="dir_tag_syntax">
    <routine name="TclDirectoryTag"/>
    <help name="DIRECTORY/TAG">
      Command: DIRECTORY/TAG
      Purpose: List tagname definitions in the tree.
      Format: DIRECTORY/TAG [tagname-wild] [/PATH]
      
      Description:

      The DIRECTORY/TAG command is used to list tagnames in the current tree. A wildcard string
      parameter can be included to list only the tags matching the wildcard string.

      If the /PATH qualifier is included the full paths of the nodes pointed to by the tagname
      will be displayed.

      Example: DIRECTORY/TAG MYT*G
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="TAG" default="*::*" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="path"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="dispatch">
    <help name="DISPATCH">
      Command: DISPATCH
      Purpose: DISPATCH and action to an action server.
      Format: DISPATCH action-node-path [/WAIT]
      
      Description:

      The DISPATCH command is used to dispatch an action node to a
      action server. If the /WAIT qualifier is included the command
      will wait for the action execution to complete.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="NODE"/>
    <qualifier name="command" syntax="dispatch_command"/>
    <qualifier name="wait" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="build" syntax="dispatch_build"/>
    <qualifier name="check" syntax="dispatch_check"/>
    <qualifier name="phase" syntax="dispatch_phase"/>
    <qualifier name="close" syntax="dispatch_close"/>
  </verb>

  <syntax name="dispatch_build">
    <help name="DISPATCH/BUILD">
      Command: DISPATCH/BUILD
      Purpose: Build a dispatch table used by the DISPATCH/PHASE command.
      Format: DISPATCH/BUILD [/MONITOR=action-server]
      Description:
      
      The DISPATCH/BUILD command finds all the actions in a tree which are
      currently turned on and builds a sorted table of actions. The actions
      are grouped by phase and ordered by sequence numbers. Actions which are
      configured to be dispatched based on dependency expressions are also
      identified. The DISPATCH/PHASE command utilizes this table when deciding
      which actions and in which order they should be dispatched to action
      servers.

      The /MONITOR qualifier is used to send messages to an action monitor
      server which are in turn transmitted to actmon processes which display
      the current status of data acquisition actions being performed.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch_build"/>
    <qualifier name="monitor" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="dispatch_check">
    <help name="DISPATCH/CHECK">
      Command: DISPATCH/CHECK [/RESET]
      Purpose: Returns a failure status if the failed essential flag is set.
               successfully.
      Format: DISPATCH/CHECK
      Description:
      
      When data acquisition phases are dispatched, a failure flag is set if
      any action marked as essential (See the SET NODE command) fails during
      execution. The DISPATCH/CHECK command checks on the current state of
      that failure flag. If the flag is set the DISPATCH/CHECK command will
      return a failure status otherwise it will return a success status.
      
      If the /RESET qualifier is used, the failure flag will be reset after
      the check is made so subsequent DISPATCH/CHECK commands will return a
      success status unless another essential action subsequently fails before
      the next DISPATCH/CHECK command is issued.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch_check"/>
    <qualifier name="reset"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="dispatch_phase">
    <help name="DISPATCH/PHASE">
      Command: DISPATCH/PHASE
      Purpose: Dispatch all the actions associated with a named phase.
      Format: DISPATCH/PHASE phase-name [/NOACTION] [/SYNCH=n] [/LOG]
              [/MONITOR=monitor-server]
      Description:
      
      The DISPATCH/PHASE command is used to dispatch all actions assigned
      to a particular phase to action servers for execution. This command
      uses the action table created by a DISPATCH/BUILD there for a
      DISPATCH/BUILD command must be given before using the DISPATCH/PHASE
      command for any pulse file. Actions are dispatched in order of the
      actions sequence number or if the sequence is an expression containing
      other nodes, the action will be dispatched if all the actions in the
      expression have completed and the expression evaluates to a true value.

      The /SYNCH qualifier can be used to synchronize all action servers based
      on the sequence numbers of the actions. Without the /SYNCH qualifier,
      all actions matching the phase specified are dispatched immediately to
      all the action servers in order of the sequence numbers. Each action
      server maintains a queue of actions and will execute those actions one
      after the other until all the actions in its queue have been executed.
      If the /SYNCH command, the actions will be dispatched in groups of the
      synch value thus synchronizing the actions across multiple servers.
      For example, a /SYNCH=10 specification would cause the DISPATCH/PHASE
      command to dispatch all the actions with sequence numbers 1 through 10
      to be dispatched to their designated action servers in sequence order.
      No other actions will be dispatched to action servers until this first
      "batch" have all completed. Then sequence numbers 11-20 would then be
      dispatched. This ensures that an action with sequence number 15 would
      on one server would not be executed before one with sequence number 10
      on another server. This is often critical during the initialization
      phase where certain types of modules such as triggering devices must
      be initialized before data acquisition devices that they trigger are
      armed.

      The /LOG qualifier will output log messages of actions being dispatched,
      started and completed. The /NOACTION can be used with the /LOG qualifier
      to log what would be dispatched but no actions would actually be
      dispatched.

      The /MONITOR qualifier is used to specify an action monitor action
      server which is used to relay action activity to actmon processes
      which display the status of action execution.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch_phase"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="PHASE_NAME" prompt="Phase" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="phase"/>
    <qualifier name="noaction"/>
    <qualifier name="synch" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="1" type="NUMBER"/>
    <qualifier name="log" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="monitor" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="dispatch_close">
    <routine name="TclDispatch_close"/>
    <help name="DISPATCH/CLOSE">
      Command: DISPATCH/CLOSE
      Purpose: Instruct MDSplus actions server(s) to close all open trees.
      Format: DISPATCH/CLOSE[/SERVER=(server1,server2...)]
      
      Description:

      The DISPATCH/CLOSE can be used to instruct an MDSplus action server to close all MDSplus
      trees the server currently has open. If the /SERVER qualifier is not included to specify
      any action servers then the current dispatch table (See: DISPATCH/BUILD and
      DISPATCH/PHASE commands) is inspected to construct a list of servers that had actions
      dispatched to them to send close instructions to. The DISPATCH/CLOSE command is typically
      used at the end of a data acquisition cycle to instruct the action server to close
      any open trees.
    </help>
    <qualifier name="close"/>
    <qualifier name="server" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>
  
  <syntax name="dispatch_command">
    <routine name="TclDispatch_command"/>
    <help name="DISPATCH/COMMAND">
      Command: DISPATCH/COMMAND
      Purpose: Dispatch an mdsdcl command to a server for execution by the server process.
      Format: DISPATCH/COMMAND/SERVER=servername[/WAIT][/TABLE=command-table] command-to-execute
      
      Description:

      The DISPATCH/COMMAND command is used to send an mdsdcl command to an MDSplus action server
      for execution by that server. The command will be executed asynchronously unless the /WAIT
      qualifier is included in the command. The /TABLE qualifier can be used to specify a
      command table to use. If the /TABLE qualifier is omitted then the command will be assumed
      to be a TCL or MDSDCL command.
    </help>
    <qualifier name="command"/>
    <qualifier name="server" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="wait"/>
    <qualifier name="table" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="TCL"/>
    <parameter name="p1" type="rest_of_line"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="do">
    <help name="DO">
      Command: DO
      Purpose: Execute an action node in the tree.
      Format: DO action-node-path
      Description:
      
      The DO command is used to execute an action node in a tree in the
      context of the current process. This can be useful for debugging
      actions but care must be taken that you are attempting to execute
      the action on a host which can actually execute the action. The
      action may need to access data acquisition hardware which might only
      be accessible by the host specified in the action so attempting to
      execute the action on another node would likely generate errors.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDoNode"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="method" syntax="do_method"/>
  </verb>

  <syntax name="do_method">
    <help name="DO/METHOD">
      Command: DO/METHOD
      Purpose: Execute a method of a device represented in the tree.
      Format: DO/METHOD device-node-path method
               [/ARG="expression"] [/IF=expression] [/OVERRIDE]
      Description:
      
      The DO/METHOD command is used to perform a method supported for the
      device type of the device collection of nodes in a tree. When using
      the DO/METHOD command you can specify any node in that device to
      identify the device. Like to DO command, you must be careful that
      the device you are trying to operate is accessible on the host where
      you are executing the command as the method is executed in your
      current process context.

      The /ARG qualifier lets you supply an argument to the method. It must be
      in the form of an tdi expression. If you need to pass a string argument
      you would do a command such as:

      TCL> DO/METHOD mydevice init /ARG="""mystring"""

      The /OVERRIDE qualifier is use to override the current on/off status
      of the device in the tree. If the device nodes are turned off and the
      /OVERRIDE qualifier is not present, then no action will be performed.

      The /IF qualifier can be used to provide an expression. The method will
      then only be executed if the evaluation of the expression generates
      an integer value with the lowest significant bit set.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDoMethod"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="object" prompt="Object" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="method" prompt="Method" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="argument" required="True" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="if" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="override"/>
  </syntax>
  
  <verb name="edit">
    <routine name="TclEdit"/>
    <help name="EDIT">
      Command: EDIT
      Purpose: Create a new MDSplus tree or open an existing tree to add nodes or tags.
      Format: EDIT treename [/SHOT=shot-number] [/NEW]
      Description:

      The EDIT command is used to edit or create an MDSplus tree file. Before you can edit or
      create a tree file you must have treename_path environment variable set to define the
      location of the tree files (i.e. mytree_path=/home/me/mytreedir).

      The /SHOT qualifier is used to specify a shot number to edit or create. If the /SHOT qualifier
      is not specified, the EDIT command will default to shot number -1, the "model" tree.

      If the /NEW qualifier is specified then a new empty tree will be created overriding any
      existing tree if one exists.

      Note: Once you are done editing a tree you must use the WRITE command to save any
      structural changes you might have made to the tree.
    </help>
    <parameter name="p1" label="FILE" prompt="File" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1" type="number"/>
    <qualifier name="new"/>
  </verb>

  <!--
  <verb name="link">
    <routine name="TclLink"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="SOURCE" prompt="Source experiment" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="DESTINATION" prompt="Destination experiment" required="True"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="mark">
    <routine name="TreeMarkIncludes"/>
  </verb>
  -->
  
  <verb name="put">
    <help name="PUT">
      Command: PUT
      Purpose: Store data into a node in the tree.
      Format: PUT node-path (expression  | [/EXTENDED] [/LF] [/EOF=xxx])
      Description:
      
      The PUT command is used to store data into a node in an MDSplus tree.
      The expression parameter is compiled into a tdi expression and stored
      into the node. If the /EXTENDED qualifier is specified, the expression
      string will be read from subsequent input lines until either an EOF
      string is read or a zero length line is read. If the /LF qualifier
      is used with the /EXTENDED qualifier, the line feeds at the end of
      each line will be included in the expression. The /LF qualifier is
      generally only useful if the expression is a quoted string containing
      line feeds. The /EOF qualifier can be used to specify an EOF string
      which would terminate the expression input. If the expression has
      zero length the node will be emptied of its data.

      Examples:

      TCL> PUT mynode 42    ! Store a integer 42 in a node
      TCL> PUT mynode ""    ! Empty a node
      TCL> PUT mynode ""this is a string"" ! Store a text string
      TCL> PUT/EXTEND mynode ! Store an integer
      PUT> 42
      PUT>
      TCL> PUT/EXTEND mynode  ! Store an integer with units
      PUT> build_with_units(42,"volts")
      PUT>
      TCL> PUT/EXTEND/LF mynode
      PUT> "This is a test
      PUT> with line feeds in the text"
      
    </help>
    <routine name="TclPutExpression"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="VALUE" prompt="Value" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EXTENDED" syntax="put_extended"/>
  </verb>
  <syntax name="put_extended">
    <routine name="TclPutExpression"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EXTENDED" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="SYMBOLS"/>
    <qualifier name="LF" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EOF" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="remove">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="REMOVE_TYPE"/>
  </verb>
  <type name="REMOVE_TYPE">
    <keyword name="TAG" syntax="remove_tag"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="remove_tag">
    <help name="REMOVE TAG">
      Command: REMOVE TAG
      Purpose: Remove a tagname from a node.
      Format: REMOVE TAG tagname
      
      Description:

      The REMOVE TAG command is used to remove a tagname from a node.
      The tree must be opened by the EDIT command to be able to remove
      a tagname from a node. The changes must be preserved by issuing a
      WRITE command before closing the tree with the CLOSE command.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclRemoveTag"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="REMOVE_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="TAGNAME" prompt="Tag" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="RENAME">
    <help name="RENAME">
       Command: RENAME
      Purpose: Rename a node in a tree.
      Format: RENAME old-node-path new-node-path [/LOG]
      
      Description:

      The RENAME command can be used to rename a node in an MDSplus tree.
      Before the RENAME command can be used the tree must be opened with
      the EDIT command. If the new-node-path specified contains parent
      nodes those parent nodes must already exist or the rename will fail.
      The changes must be preserved by issuing a WRITE command before
      closing the tree with the CLOSE command.

      The /LOG qualifier can be used to display log messages indicating
      the rename operation.
    </help>
   <routine name="TclRename"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="SOURCE" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="DEST" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="LOG"/>
  </verb>

  <!--
  <verb name="rundown">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="RUNDOWN_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="RUNDOWN_TYPE">
    <keyword name="TREE" syntax="rundown_tree"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="rundown_tree">
    <routine name="TclRundownTree"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="RUNDOWN_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="FILE" prompt="File" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1"/>
    <qualifier name="force_exit"/>
    <qualifier name="subtrees"/>
    </syntax>
    -->

  <verb name="set">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="SET_TYPE">
    <keyword name="ATTRIBUTE" syntax="set_attribute"/>"
    <keyword name="CURRENT" syntax="set_current"/>"
    <keyword name="DEFAULT" syntax="set_default"/>"
    <keyword name="NODE" syntax="set_node"/>"
    <keyword name="READONLY" syntax="set_readonly"/>
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="set_server"/>"
    <keyword name="TREE" syntax="set_tree"/>"
    <keyword name="VIEW" syntax="set_view"/>"
    <keyword name="VERSIONS" syntax="set_versions"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="set_attribute">
    <help name="SET ATTRIBUTE">
      Command: SET ATTRIBUTE
      Purpose: Add a named attribute to a node.
      Format: SET ATTRIBUTE node-path/NAME=attribute-name (value | /EXTENDED)
      
      Description:

      The SET ATTRIBUTE command will add an attribute to a node as named with
      the /NAME qualifier. The value argument is used to specify the value of
      the named attribute and is compiled as a TDI expression. The /EXTENDED
      qualifier can be specified to enable you to supply the expression content
      in following lines ended by a blank line. This provides an easy way to
      add quoted strings that would otherwise require special handling in the
      main command line.

      Examples:

      TCL> SET ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=special 42
      TCL> SET ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=myattr/EXTENDED
      build_with_units(42,"volts")

      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=special
      42
      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode/name=myattr
      BUILD_WITH_UNITS(42,"volts")

      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode
      Defined attributes for this node:
      myattr
      special
    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetAttribute"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p3" label="VALUE" prompt="Value" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="NAME" nonnegatable="True" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EXTENDED" syntax="set_attribute_extended"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_attribute_extended">
    <routine name="TclSetAttribute"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EXTENDED" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="SYMBOLS"/>
    <qualifier name="LF" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="EOF" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="NAME" nonnegatable="True" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_current">
    <help name="SET CURRENT">
      Command: SET CURRENT
      Purpose: Set the current shot for a tree.
      Format: SET CURRENT treename (shot-number-expression | /INCREMENT)
      
      Description:

      The SET CURRENT command is used to designate a "current" shot for a given
      tree. When opening a tree the user can specify the reserved shot number 0 to
      designate opening the "current" shot for that tree. Typically during experiment
      shot cycles the "current" shot for the main tree is incremented so that
      applications can reference shot 0 and always be looking at the latest/"current"
      shot. The shot number can either be expression by a shot number expression, the
      simplest being just an integer value, or you can use the /INCREMENT qualifier
      to make the current shot the previous current shot number plus one.

      Examples:

        TCL> SET CURRENT CMOD 1000
        TCL> SET CURRENT CMOD "current_shot('cmod')+2"
        TCL> SHOW CURRENT CMOD
        Current shot is 1002

      Note: The shot number is a signed 32-bit integer so the largest
      value for a shot number is 2147483647. Also except for the model,
      shot number -1 and the "current" shot, shot number 0, all shot
      numbers must be between 1 and 2147483647.

    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetCurrent"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="experiment" prompt="Experiment" required="True"/>
    <parameter name="p3" label="shot"/>
    <qualifier name="increment"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_view">
    <help name="SET VIEW">
      Command: SET VIEW
      Purpose: Set a instance at time for browsing data in a tree.
      Format: SET VIEW date-time-specifier
      
      Description:

      The SET VIEW command is used to set the time context for examining
      the contents of a MDSplus tree. If data versioning is enabled on
      a tree then a history of data entries for each node is kept each
      being timestamped. When you specify a "view" date and time the commands
      such as DIRECTORY, DECOMPILE and SHOW DATA will present a description
      of the data the same as if you issued those commands at that particular
      time.

      The date-time-specifier must be in the format:
         dd-mon-yyyy hh:mm:ss where:
	    dd    - the day of the month, integer such as 29.
	    mon   - the first three characters of the month (english) such as JAN.
	    yyyy  - the year, integer such as 2015.
	    hh    - the hour of the day, integer 0-23.
	    mm    - the minute, integer 0-59.
	    ss    - the seconds, integer 0-59
	 or special keyword "NOW" meaning the current time.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetView"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="DATE" prompt="Date" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_default">
    <help name="SET DEFAULT">
      Command: SET DEFAULT
      Purpose: Set your current location in an open tree.
      Format: SET DEFAULT node-path
      
      Description:

      The SET DEFAULT is similar to a cd command in a file system.
      The default location in the tree hierarchy affects things like
      the DIRECTORY command as well as all commands that take a node-path
      as an argument. Node paths specified as relative path strings are
      resolved by finding the node relative to the current default location
      in the tree.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetDefault"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_node">
    <help name="SET NODE">
      Command: SET NODE
      Purpose: Modify node characteristics in an MDSplus tree.
      Format: SET NODE node-path-wild /option[/option...]
      Description:

      The SET NODE command is used to change the characteristics of one
      or more nodes in an MDSplus tree. The 'option' in the Format above
      is one of the following:

      ON                    - turn node "on"
      OFF                   - turn node "off"
      [NO]SUBTREE           - make node a subtree reference (or not)
                              available only during EDIT
      [NO]WRITE_ONCE        - make node write once (or not)
      [NO]COMPRESS_ON_PUT   - turn on or off automatic compression
      [NO]COMPRESS_SEGMENTS - turn on or off automatice segment compression
      [NO]DO_NOT_COMPRESS   - turn off any data compression on the node
      [NO]SHOT_WRITE        - enable writing to this node in a pulse file
      [NO]MODEL_WRITE       - enable writing to this node in shot -1
      [NO]INCLUDED          - include this subtree in 'conditional' create pulse
      [NO]ESSENTIAL         - make this node 'essential' for DISPATCH/CHECK
      LOG                   - log node changes
      STATUS=n              - Write a status value to a node (usually action nodes).

      All nodes in an MDSplus tree have a set of attributes, some are set automatically
      when data is stored, some are set when the nodes are first added to a tree and
      some are modifiable by this command. The options indicated with a '[NO]' prefix
      indicates that the option can be negated. For example, using the command
      SET NODE gub/WRITE_ONCE will set a flag in the nodes characteristics that
      indicates that data can only be written once after which the data cannot be
      overwritten. Using the command SET NODE gub/NOWRITE_ONCE clears that "write once"
      flag thus enabling the node to be overwritten with new data.

    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetNode"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODENAME" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="SUBTREE"/>
    <qualifier name="ON"/>
    <qualifier name="OFF"/>
    <qualifier name="WRITE_ONCE"/>
    <qualifier name="CACHED"/>
    <qualifier name="COMPRESS_ON_PUT"/>
    <qualifier name="COMPRESS_SEGMENTS"/>
    <qualifier name="DO_NOT_COMPRESS"/>
    <qualifier name="SHOT_WRITE"/>
    <qualifier name="MODEL_WRITE"/>
    <qualifier name="INCLUDED"/>
    <qualifier name="LOG"/>
    <qualifier name="ESSENTIAL"/>
    <qualifier name="STATUS" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_server">
    <help name="SET SERVER">
      Command: SET SERVER
      Purpose: Change the logging mode for an action server.
      Format: SET SERVER/LOG=(LOG | STATISTICS | NONE)
      Description:

      Action servers by default will write log messages to stdout when
      they are dispatched and action, when they begin an action and
      when the complete an action. This is the type of logging produced
      by using /LOG=LOG. The /LOG=STATISTICS produces more detailed
      logs indicating the CPU and memory resources used during the
      execution of an action. The /LOG=NONE disables standard logging
      of action execution.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch_set_server"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="server" prompt="Server" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="log" nonnegatable="True" default="ACTIONS" type="logging_type"/>
  </syntax>

  <type name="logging_type">
    <keyword name="NONE" default="0" type="NUMBER"/>
    <keyword name="ACTIONS" defaulted="True" default="1" type="NUMBER"/>
    <keyword name="STATISTICS" default="2" type="NUMBER"/>
  </type>

  <syntax name="set_readonly">
    <help name="SET READONLY">
      Command: SET READONLY
      Purpose: Make tree readonly.
      Format: SET READONLY [/OFF]
      Description:

      The SET READONLY command is used to make a tree readonly. No store of
      data or change of node characteristics is permitted. This is an edit
      operation and a WRITE command must be performed to save the readonly
      property of a tree. Use the /OFF qualifier to disable the readonly
      setting to make the tree writable again.

    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetReadonly"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <qualifier name="OFF"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_tree">
    <help name="SET TREE">
      Command: SET TREE
      Purpose: Open an MDSplus tree.
      Format: SET TREE tree-name[,subtree1[,subtree2,]] [/SHOT=shot-number] [/READONLY]
      Description:

      The SET TREE command is used to open an MDSplus tree. If subtree names are
      included in the tree-name parameter then only those trees will be opened if they
      are available. The /SHOT qualifier can be used to specify a particular shot
      number to open. The shot number can be a TDI expression. If omitted, the
      "model" tree or shot -1 is opened. If the /READONLY qualifier is included then
      the tree is opened in a readonly mode and no changes can be made to the nodes
      or their data.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetTree"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="FILE" prompt="File" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1"/>
    <qualifier name="readonly"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="set_versions">
    <help name="SET VERSIONS">
      Command: SET VERSIONS
      Purpose: Enable or disable data versioning in a tree.
      Format: SET VERSIONS [/[NO]MODEL] [/[NO]SHOT]
      Description:

      The SET VERSIONS command is used to enable or disable data versioning in an
      MDSplus tree. When versioning is enabled, new data records stored to a node
      do not overwrite the existing data but instead are added to a list of data
      records for that node. Each new data record is timestamped and you can use
      the SET VIEW command to designate a particular reference time so that your
      view would be equivalent to having examined the tree at that particular
      date and time. You can enable versioning for either the model or pulse files
      or both.

      NOTE: Data versioning is not supported for segmented data records.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetVersions"/>
    <qualifier name="MODEL"/>
    <qualifier name="SHOT"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="SETEVENT">
    <help name="SETEVENT">
      Command: SETEVENT
      Purpose: Issue an MDSplus event.
      Format: SETEVENT eventname
      Description:

      The SETEVENT command can be used to issue an MDSplus event. MDSplus events
      are named happenings that other processes can wait for by name. See the
      WFEVENT command. The TCL command does not currently support sending a data
      message with the event.

    </help>
    <routine name="TclSetEvent"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="EVENT" prompt="Event" required="True"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="show">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="show_TYPE">
    <keyword name="ATTRIBUTE" syntax="show_attribute"/>"
    <keyword name="CURRENT" syntax="show_current"/>"
    <keyword name="DATA" syntax="show_data"/>"
    <keyword name="DB" syntax="show_db"/>"
    <keyword name="DEFAULT" syntax="show_default"/>"
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="show_server"/>"
    <keyword name="VERSION" syntax="show_version"/>"
    <keyword name="VERSIONS" syntax="show_versions"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="show_attribute">
    <help name="SHOW ATTRIBUTE">
      Command: SHOW ATTRIBUTE
      Purpose: Show the contents of a nodes "named" attribute.
      Format: SHOW ATTRIBUTE/NAME=attribute-name
      Description:

      The SHOW ATTRIBUTE command is used to display the contents of a node's
      named attribute.

      TCL> SET ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=special 42
      TCL> SET ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=myattr/EXTENDED
      build_with_units(42,"volts")

      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode/NAME=special
      42
      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode/name=myattr
      BUILD_WITH_UNITS(42,"volts")

      TCL> SHOW ATTRIBUTE mynode
      Defined attributes for this node:
      myattr
      special

    </help>
    <routine name="TclShowAttribute"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="node" prompt="Node" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="name" nonnegatable="True" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_current">
    <help name="SHOW CURRENT">
      Command: SHOW CURRENT
      Purpose: Show the current shot for a given tree.
      Format: SHOW CURRENT treename
      Description:

      The SHOW CURRENT command is useful to display the current shot for
      a particular tree. See HELP SET CURRENT for more information on the
      meaning of "current" shot.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclShowCurrent"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="SET_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="experiment" prompt="Experiment" required="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_data">
    <help name="SHOW DATA">
      Command: SHOW DATA
      Purpose: Display the data contents of a node in an mdsplus tree.
      Format: SHOW DATA node-path[,node-path,...]
      Description:

      The SHOW DATA command will display the data stored in a node in a tree.
      Unlike the DECOMPILE command, the SHOW DATA shows the data structure
      stored in the node as well as following node references recursively
      if an expression store in a node references other nodes in the tree.

    </help>
    <routine name="TclShowData"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="NODE" prompt="Node" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_db">
     <help name="SHOW DB">
      Command: SHOW DB
      Purpose: Display the current tree and default node opened in the current
               process.
      Format: SHOW DB
      Description:

      The SHOW DB can be used to display what the current tree context is. It
      displays the tree and shot, open mode and the current default node in the
      tree.

      Example:

      TCL> SHOW DB
      000  MAIN                              shot: -1 [\MAIN::TOP]

     </help>
   <routine name="TclShowDB"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_default">
     <help name="SHOW DEFAULT">
      Command: SHOW DEFAULT
      Purpose: Display the current default node.
      Format: SHOW DEFAULT
      Description:

      The SHOW DEFAULT can be used to display what the current default node
      location in the opened tree.

      Example:

      TCL> SHOW DEFAULT
      \MAIN::TOP

     </help>
    <routine name="TclShowDefault"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_server">
    <help name="SHOW SERVER">
      Command: SHOW SERVER
      Purpose: Display the current status of one or more action servers.
      Format: SHOW SERVER server-spec[,server-spec] [/NOOUTPUT]
      Description:

      The SHOW SERVER command can be used to query action servers to see what,
      if anything, they are currently working on. The /NOOUTPUT command can
      be useful to just detect if there is a problem accessing an action server.
      
      Wildcard characters can be used in the server name but only if the following
      conditions are met:
      1) all the servers are logging their output to a single log directory.
      2) the server logs are named the same as the string you would use to
         communicate with that server (i.e. myhost-name:8100).
      3) there is an environment variable called "MDSIP_SERVER_LOGDIR" defined
         pointing to that directory.
      4) Your process has access to that directory.

      When wildcards are used in the server name the log directory is searched for
      logfiles matching the wildcard specification and then the log file name is used
      for the server specication when connecting to that server.
      Example:

      TCL> show server localhost:9000
      Checking server: localhost:9000
      Tue Feb 10 15:51:27 2015, fc21-vm:9000, logging disabled, Inactive

    </help>
   <routine name="TclDispatch_show_server"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="stop_type"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="server_name" prompt="Server" required="True" list="True"/>
    <qualifier name="output" defaulted="True"/>
    <qualifier name="full"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_version">
    <helpmissing />
    <image name="Mdsdcl"/>
    <routine name="mdsdcl_show_version"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
  </syntax>

  <syntax name="show_versions">
    <help name="SHOW VERSIONS">
      Command: SHOW VERSIONS
      Purpose: Show whether or not data versioning is enabled for the current tree.
      Format: SHOW VERSIONS

      Description:

      The SHOW VERSIONS command is used to display the current data versioning
      settings for the current tree.

      Example:

      TCL> SET TREE main
      TCL> SHOW VERSIONS
        Versions are disabled in the model file and disabled in the shot file.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclShowVersions"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="show_TYPE"/>
  </syntax>

  <!--
  <verb name="start">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="start_TYPE"/>
  </verb>

  <syntax name="start_server">
    <routine name="TclDispatch_start_server"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="start_type"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="server" prompt="Server" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <type name="start_TYPE">
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="start_server"/>"
    </type>
    -->

  <verb name="stop">
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="stop_type"/>
  </verb>

  <type name="stop_type">
    <keyword name="SERVER" syntax="stop_server"/>"
  </type>

  <syntax name="stop_server">
    <help name="STOP SERVER">

      Command: STOP SERVER
      Purpose: Stop/restart one or more MDSplus action servers.
      Format: STOP SERVER server-spec[,server-spec]
      Description:

      The STOP SERVER command can be used to stop one or more action servers.
      Normally MDSplus action servers are configured to restart automatically so
      this command effectively will restart an action server. It is not uncommon
      to restart action servers at some interval such as once per day to recover
      fragmented virtual memory within the action server process. Other reasons
      for stopping an action server might be to reset I/O channels to data acquisition
      devices which might become non-responsive or device support code may introduce
      memory leaks which may require the process to be restarted to release virtual
      memory.
      
      Unlike the SHOW SERVER command, Wildcard characters cannot be used in the
      server-spec string.
 
    </help>
    <routine name="TclDispatch_stop_server"/>
    <parameter name="p1" prompt="What" required="True" type="stop_type"/>
    <parameter name="p2" label="servnam" prompt="Server" required="True" list="True"/>
  </syntax>

  <verb name="verify">
    <help name="VERIFY">

      Command: VERIFY
      Purpose: Examine a tree structure to ensure it is valid and intact.
      Format: VERIFY
      Description:

      The VERIFY command can be used to check the integrety of the currently opened
      tree to ensure that the tree structure representation is valid and complete.
      The VERIFY command is a useful diagnostic tool if file system or disk corruption
      problems have been detected on the storage device where the tree files are
      stored. If damage to the tree (file name such as mytree_nnn.tree) is discovered,
      it is usually safe to copy the tree file from an adjacent shot since the tree
      file contains only the tree structure and not the data or characteristics of
      the nodes in the tree.

      The VERIFY command will display a count of the nodes in the tree. If there are
      subtree nodes included in the tree those nodes will be listed as "other" in the
      node counts.

      Example:

      TCL> SET TREE mytree
      TCL> VERIFY
      Node summary:
        Allocated = 7/14
        Free      = 7/14
        Other     = 0/14
      
    </help>
    <routine name="TclVerifyTree"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="WFEVENT">
    <help name="WFEVENT">

      Command: WFEVENT
      Purpose: Wait for an MDSplus event to be issued.
      Format: WFEVENT event-name /TIMEOUT=seconds
      Description:

      The WFEVENT command can be used to wait for an MDSplus event to be issued. MDSplus events
      are named occurrences that can be issued by other processes on the same or different host
      computers. The WFEVENT command will not complete until the MDSplus event is generated.
      The /TIMEOUT qualifier can be specified to cause the wait to time out if no event is generated
      within the specified number of seconds.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclWfevent"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="event" prompt="Event" required="True"/>
    <qualifier name="TIMEOUT" required="True" defaulted="True" default="0"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="write">
    <help name="WRITE">
      Command: WRITE
      Purpose: Write out a tree structure preserving changes made via
               editing commands.
      Format: WRITE [treename] [/SHOT=shot-number]
      
      Description:

      The WRITE command is used to write out a new tree to preserve any
      changes using editing commands such as those listed in:
      HELP EDIT COMMANDS.

      If the treename parameter or /SHOT qualifier is omitted the tree
      and shot specified with the EDIT command is assumed. If a tree
      is modified by edit commands and a WRITE command is not issued,
      those changes will be discarded.
    </help>
    <routine name="TclWrite"/>
    <parameter name="p1" label="FILE"/>
    <qualifier name="shotid" defaulted="True" nonnegatable="True" default="-1" type="number"/>
  </verb>

  <verb name="ls" type="rest_of_line">
    <routine name="TclLs"/>
  </verb>
  
</module>
